<root name="PURPOSE">
    <questionnaire>
        <category_1>
            <name>Motivation</name>
            <code>M</code>
            <description>The questions in this category are primarily intended to encourage dataset creators to clearly articulate their reasons for creating the dataset and to promote transparency about funding interests.</description>
            <questions>
                <Q0>For what purpose was the dataset created?</Q0>
                <Q1>Who created the dataset (e.g., which team, research group) and on behalf of which entity (e.g., company, institution, organization)?</Q1>
                <Q2>Who funded the creation of the dataset?</Q2>
                <Q3>Any other comments?</Q3>
            </questions>
            <messages>
                <M0>Was there a specific task in mind? Was there a specific gap that needed to be filled? Please provide a description.</M0>
                <M1 />
                <M2>If there is an associated grant, please provide the name of the grantor and the grant name and number.</M2>
                <M3 />
            </messages>
            <answers>
                <A0>The present dataset was created for machine learning in order to improve the prediction of bloodstream infections. The dataset combines clinical blood parameters, age, sex as well as previous admissions to blood culturing results (negative and positive) and resistance profile of the infecting pathogen over a period of more than 10 years. </A0>
                <A1>Dept. of Clinical Microbiology, Rigshospitalet created the dataset In collaboration with dept. of clinical Biochemistry,  Rigshospitalet </A1>
                <A2 />
                <A3>Name of person answering questions: 
Karen Leth Nielsen Karen.leth.nielsen.01@regionh.dk
Frederik Bo&#235;tius Hertz Frederik.boetius.hertz@regionh.dk
Karen Leth Nielsen Karen.Leth.Nielsen.01@regionh.dk </A3>
            </answers>
        </category_1>
        <category_2>
            <name>Composition</name>
            <code>C</code>
            <description>Most of these questions are intended to provide dataset consumers with the information they need to make informed decisions about using the dataset for specific tasks. The answers to some of these questions reveal information about compliance with the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) or comparable regulations in other jurisdictions.</description>
            <questions>
                <Q0>What do the instances that comprise the dataset represent (e.g., samples, images, people)?</Q0>
                <Q1>How many instances are there in total?</Q1>
                <Q2>Does the dataset contain all possible instances or is it a sample (not necessarily random) of instances from a larger set?</Q2>
                <Q3>What data does each instance consist of?</Q3>
                <Q4>Is there a label, target, or outcome (e.g., mortality) associated with each instance?</Q4>
                <Q5>Is any information missing from individual instances?</Q5>
                <Q6>Are relationships between individual instances made explicit (e.g., familial links, or samples derived from the same patient or same exposure)?</Q6>
                <Q7>Are there recommended data splits (e.g., training, development/validation, testing)?</Q7>
                <Q8>Are there any errors, sources of noise, or redundancies in the dataset?</Q8>
                <Q9>Is the dataset self-contained, or does it link to or otherwise rely on external resources (e.g., websites, public databases, other datasets and/or private silos)?</Q9>
                <Q10>Does the dataset contain data that might be considered confidential (e.g., data that is protected by legal privilege or by doctor-patient confidentiality, data that includes the content of individuals&#8217; non-public communications)?</Q10>
                <Q11>Does the dataset contain data that, if viewed directly, might be offensive, insulting, threatening, or might otherwise cause anxiety?</Q11>
                <Q12>Does the dataset not relate to people (e.g., animals, cell lines, environment)?</Q12>
                <Q13>Does the dataset identify any subpopulations (e.g., by age, gender, etc.)?</Q13>
                <Q14>Is it possible to identify individuals (i.e., one or more natural persons), either directly or indirectly (i.e., in combination with other data) from the dataset?</Q14>
                <Q15>Does the dataset contain data that might be considered sensitive in any way (e.g., data that reveals racial or ethnic origins, sexual orientations, religious beliefs, political opinions or union memberships, or locations; financial or health data; biometric or genetic data; forms of government identification, such as social security numbers; criminal history)?</Q15>
                <Q16>Any other comments?</Q16>
            </questions>
            <messages>
                <M0>Are there multiple types of instances (e.g., samples, images, and people), interactions (e.g., nodes and edges), resolutions (e.g., genetic data, single cell expression vs. tissue expression, cell counts, different image technologies, etc.)? Please provide a description.</M0>
                <M1>Provide an exact integer value for each type mentioned in question C1.</M1>
                <M2>f the dataset is a sample, then what is the larger set? Is the sample representative of the larger set (e.g., geographic coverage)? If so, please describe how this representativeness was validated/verified. If it is not representative of the larger set, please describe why not (e.g., an active decision to cover a more diverse range of instances, because instances were withheld or unavailable).</M2>
                <M3>&#8220;Raw&#8221; data (e.g., unprocessed text or images) or features? In either case, please provide a description.</M3>
                <M4>If so, please provide a description and indicate its actual presence within the dataset or whether it is represented by a proxy or compounded (e.g., a multi-cause event).</M4>
                <M5>If so, please provide a description, explaining why this information is missing (e.g., because it was unavailable). This does not include intentionally removed information, but might include, e.g., redacted text.</M5>
                <M6>If so, please describe how these relationships are made explicit.</M6>
                <M7>If so, please provide a description of these splits, explaining the rationale behind them.</M7>
                <M8>If so, please provide a description.</M8>
                <M9>If it links to or relies on external resources, a) are there guarantees that they will exist, and remain constant, over time; b) are there official archival versions of the complete dataset (i.e., including the external resources as they existed at the time the dataset was created); c) are there any restrictions (e.g., licenses, fees) associated with any of the external resources that might apply to a future user? Please provide descriptions of all external resources and any restrictions associated with them, as well as links or other access points, as appropriate.</M9>
                <M10>If so, please provide a description.</M10>
                <M11>If so, please describe why.</M11>
                <M12>A short answer is sufficient. If no relation to people, you may skip the remaining questions in this section.</M12>
                <M13>If so, please describe how these subpopulations are identified and provide a description of their respective distributions within the dataset.</M13>
                <M14>If so, please describe how.</M14>
                <M15>If so, please provide a description.</M15>
                <M16 />
            </messages>
            <answers>
                <A0>The whole dataset represents the event or lack thereof of a step leading to activation of the immune response. D1: Peptides measured in a stability assay, investigating whether a there is a complex formed with the MHC molecule and how stable that complex is. Two columns: one with peptide (9 amino acids), one with measurement. ELISA measurement. The MS dataset represents peptide ligands investigated to be binding to MHC. D2: Each instance is a peptide found to be bound to MHC. Peptides vary in length. Only positive (binding) instances are present. Peptides with modifications (e.g. + OX(M14)) can be disregarded.</A0>
                <A1>D1: 4919 (each instance represents a unique peptide:MHC) D2: 2827 (each instance represents a unique peptide:MHC)</A1>
                <A2>The datasets represent a small sample from the whole peptide space. If peptides are tested randomly only around 1% of the measured peptides binds to MHC. The provided datasets are thus enriched and allow building a model that can contain features describing the studied problem.</A2>
                <A3>Each data instance is a measurement of stability of a unique peptide:MHC complex, in case of the Stability dataset. For the MS datasets each instance is representing whether the peptide was/was not present in the eluted ligands.</A3>
                <A4>Yes, each peptide sequence is associated with an outcome. D1: normalized stability, measured with ELISA. Normalisation (% stability) is per batch, to a reference peptide (100%). D2: detection of the peptide via Mass Spec (binding/non-binding) binary value.</A4>
                <A5>No</A5>
                <A6>No</A6>
                <A7>For iterative models it is common to use 5-fold cross validation. Sometimes nested, such that there is also one rotating bin left for early stopping.</A7>
                <A8>Yes. There are several duplicates in D1. Some of which are the control measurements, those can be disregarded when using the data. The control peptides are longer than 9 residues. D1 is known to have less noise than D2.</A8>
                <A9>It is self-contained. Validation data (known immunogenic peptides) can be found at IEDB (www.iedb.org). One-hot encoding can be done without external data, but it is also possible to use evolutionary information (BLOSUM) or other distance matrix to encode each of the amino acids.</A9>
                <A10>Yes, D1 is confidential, unpublished and with commercial interest. Anyone needs to sign an NDA.</A10>
                <A11>The data is related to a mouse genotype (allele). When expanding this type of models it is important to consider that genotypes are covered in an unbiased manner (some alleles are more prevalent in some ethnicities).</A11>
                <A12>Yes, it does not relate to people. The dataset relates to mice.</A12>
                <A13 />
                <A14 />
                <A15 />
                <A16>No</A16>
            </answers>
        </category_2>
        <category_3>
            <name>Collection Process</name>
            <code>L</code>
            <description>If possible, dataset creators should read through these questions prior to any data collection to flag potential issues and then provide answers once collection is complete. In addition to the goals of the prior category, the answers to questions here may provide information that allow others to reconstruct the dataset without access to it.</description>
            <questions>
                <Q0>How was the data associated with each instance acquired?</Q0>
                <Q1>What mechanisms or procedures were used to collect the data (e.g., hardware apparatus or sensor, manual human curation, software program, software API)?</Q1>
                <Q2>If the dataset is a sample from a larger set, what was the sampling strategy (e.g., deterministic, probabilistic with specific sampling probabilities)?</Q2>
                <Q3> Who was involved in the data collection process (e.g., students, crowdworkers, contractors) and how were they compensated (e.g., salaried, immaterial through prizes / authorship / etc) and how much (e.g., according to competitive scales mandated by [insert body or institution])?</Q3>
                <Q4>Over what timeframe was the data collected?</Q4>
                <Q5>Were any ethical review processes conducted (e.g., by an institutional review board)?</Q5>
                <Q6>Does the dataset not relate to people (e.g., animals, cell lines, environment)?</Q6>
                <Q7>Did you collect the data from the individuals in question directly, or obtain it via third parties or other sources (e.g., websites)?</Q7>
                <Q8>Were the individuals in question notified about the data collection?</Q8>
                <Q9>Did the individuals in question consent to the collection and use of their data?</Q9>
                <Q10> If consent was obtained, were the consenting individuals provided with a mechanism to revoke their consent in the future or for certain uses?</Q10>
                <Q11>Has an analysis of the potential impact of the dataset and its use on data subjects (e.g., a data protection impact analysis) been conducted?</Q11>
                <Q12>Any other comments?</Q12>
            </questions>
            <messages>
                <M0>Was the data directly observable (e.g., raw text, instrument measurements), reported by subjects/physicians (e.g., survey responses), or indirectly inferred/derived from other data (e.g., part-of-speech tags, model-based guesses, scores, etc.)? If data was reported by subjects or indirectly inferred/derived from other data, was the data validated/verified? If so, please describe how.</M0>
                <M1>How were these mechanisms or procedures validated?</M1>
                <M2>Please describe.</M2>
                <M3 />
                <M4>Does this timeframe match the creation timeframe of the data associated with the instances (e.g., recent data from old biobanked samples, or recent data dump from a 5-year-old registry)? If not, please describe the time frame in which the data associated with the instances was created.</M4>
                <M5>If so, please provide a description of these review processes, including the outcomes, as well as a link or other access point to any supporting documentation.</M5>
                <M6>A short answer is sufficient. If no relation to people, you may skip the remaining questions in this section.</M6>
                <M7>Please explain.</M7>
                <M8>If so, please describe (or show with screenshots or other information) how notice was provided, and provide a link or other access point to, or otherwise reproduce, the exact language of the notification itself.</M8>
                <M9>If so, please describe (or show with screenshots or other information) how consent was requested and provided, and provide a link or other access point to, or otherwise reproduce, the exact language to which the individuals consented.</M9>
                <M10>If so, please provide a description, as well as a link or other access point to the mechanism (if appropriate).</M10>
                <M11>If so, please provide a description of this analysis, including the outcomes, as well as a link or other access point to any supporting documentation.</M11>
                <M12 />
            </messages>
            <answers>
                <A0>Data was directly observed using an instrument. In the case of stability measurements the data is expressed as a binding percentage to a known stable binder.</A0>
                <A1>D1: ELISA; D2: Mass Spectroscopy</A1>
                <A2>Sampling strategies include selection with MS and known T cell epitopes from databases.</A2>
                <A3>D1: Employees at Immunitrack payed by Immunitrack ApS and Innovation Foundation. D2: Sofron et al. 2016 (doi: 10.1002/eji.201545930)</A3>
                <A4>Not relevant.</A4>
                <A5>No, not necessary.</A5>
                <A6>Yes, it relates to mice.</A6>
                <A7 />
                <A8 />
                <A9 />
                <A10 />
                <A11 />
                <A12>No</A12>
            </answers>
        </category_3>
        <category_4>
            <name>Preprocessing, Cleaning, Labling</name>
            <code>P</code>
            <description>If possible, dataset creators should read through these questions prior to any preprocessing, cleaning, or labeling and then provide answers once these tasks are complete. The questions in this category are intended to provide dataset consumers with the information they need to determine whether the &#8220;raw&#8221; data has been processed in ways that are compatible with their chosen tasks.</description>
            <questions>
                <Q0>Was any preprocessing/cleaning/labeling of the data done (e.g., discretization or bucketing, tokenization, part-of-speech tagging, SIFT feature extraction, removal of instances, processing of missing values)?</Q0>
                <Q1>Was the &#8220;raw&#8221; data saved in addition to the preprocessed/cleaned/labeled data (e.g., to support unanticipated future uses)?</Q1>
                <Q2>Is the software used to preprocess/clean/label the instances available?</Q2>
                <Q3>Any other comments?</Q3>
            </questions>
            <messages>
                <M0>If so, please provide a description. If not, you may skip the remainder of the questions in this section.</M0>
                <M1>If so, is it available and needs to be done to gain access? If open without restriction then please describe a means to access this &#8220;raw&#8221; data.</M1>
                <M2>If so, please provide a link or other access point and describe with enough detail so that others might reproduce it. If a custom script was used will you include it within the MAIDS repository or otherwise make it available?</M2>
                <M3 />
            </messages>
            <answers>
                <A0>Yes, the stability data is normalized as a percentage in relation to a known stable binder (control).</A0>
                <A1>Yes</A1>
                <A2>Processing of the stability data was done using Microsoft Excel.</A2>
                <A3>No</A3>
            </answers>
        </category_4>
        <category_5>
            <name>Uses</name>
            <code>U</code>
            <description>These questions are intended to encourage dataset creators to reflect on the tasks for which the dataset should and should not be used. By explicitly highlighting these tasks, dataset creators can help dataset consumers to make informed decisions, thereby avoiding potential risks or harm.</description>
            <questions>
                <Q0>Has the dataset been used for any tasks already?</Q0>
                <Q1>Is there a repository that links to any or all papers or systems that use the dataset?</Q1>
                <Q2>What (other) tasks could the dataset be used for?</Q2>
                <Q3>Is there anything about the composition of the dataset or the way it was collected and preprocessed/cleaned/labeled that might impact future uses?</Q3>
                <Q4>Are there tasks for which the dataset should not be used?</Q4>
                <Q5>Any other comments?</Q5>
            </questions>
            <messages>
                <M0>hers determine the value of this dataset by example.</M0>
                <M1>If so, please provide a link or other access point. Will you compile such a list and make it available in the MAIDS repository?</M1>
                <M2>Please provide as much inspiration as you can. Distinguish between tasks the dataset is ideal for versus those tasks where the dataset is not entirely suited. Describe why the dataset might not be suitable </M2>
                <M3>For example, is there anything that a future user might need to know to avoid uses that could result in unfair treatment of individuals or groups (e.g., stereotyping, quality of service issues) or other undesirable harms (e.g., financial harms, legal risks) If so, please provide a description. Is there anything a future user could do to mitigate these undesirable harms?</M3>
                <M4>If so, please provide a description.</M4>
                <M5 />
            </messages>
            <answers>
                <A0>D1: data is novel. D2: Sofron et al. 2016 (doi: 10.1002/eji.201545930)</A0>
                <A1>No</A1>
                <A2>Vaccine design for mice. Understanding the biology and binding preference of IAB.</A2>
                <A3>Data has commercial interest, is confidential and is under NDA. Findings can be published in agreement with Immunitrack ApS. The raw data can also be published with the paper, if needed, and in agreement with Immunitrack ApS (Who are eager to publish a nice paper on this).</A3>
                <A4>Data and any use and application is confidential, and should be discussed with Immunitrack ApS.</A4>
                <A5>No</A5>
            </answers>
        </category_5>
        <category_6>
            <name>Distribution</name>
            <code>D</code>
            <description>Dataset creators should provide answers to these questions prior to distributing the dataset either internally within the entity on behalf of which the dataset was created or externally to third parties.</description>
            <questions>
                <Q0>Will the dataset be distributed to third parties outside of the entity (e.g., company, institution, organization) on behalf of which the dataset was created</Q0>
                <Q1>How will the dataset be distributed (e.g., tarball on website, API, GitHub)?</Q1>
                <Q2>When will the dataset be distributed?</Q2>
                <Q3>Will the dataset be distributed under a copyright or other intellectual property (IP) license, and/or under applicable terms of use (ToU)?</Q3>
                <Q4>Have any third-parties imposed IP-based or other restrictions on the data associated with the instances?</Q4>
                <Q5>Do any export controls or other regulatory restrictions apply to the dataset or to individual instances?</Q5>
                <Q6>Any other comments?</Q6>
            </questions>
            <messages>
                <M0>If so, please provide a description. If not, then disregard the rest of the questions.</M0>
                <M1>Does the dataset have a digital object identifier (DOI)?</M1>
                <M2>A cautious response is more useful than an optimistic one.</M2>
                <M3>If so, please describe this license and/or ToU, and provide a link or other access point to, or otherwise reproduce, any relevant licensing terms or ToU, as well as any fees associated with these restrictions.</M3>
                <M4>If so, please describe these restrictions, and provide a link or other access point to, or otherwise reproduce, any relevant licensing terms, as well as any fees associated with these restrictions.</M4>
                <M5>If so, please describe these restrictions, and provide a link or other access point to, or otherwise reproduce, any supporting documentation.</M5>
                <M6 />
            </messages>
            <answers>
                <A0>No, not allowed.</A0>
                <A1>Should stay on server.</A1>
                <A2>For developers under NDA: When needed. For public: At time of publication.</A2>
                <A3>Yes. Attached NDA.</A3>
                <A4>Yes. Patent pending.</A4>
                <A5>No</A5>
                <A6>No</A6>
            </answers>
        </category_6>
        <category_7>
            <name>Maintenance</name>
            <code>T</code>
            <description>As with the previous category, dataset creators should provide answers to these questions prior to distributing the dataset. These questions are intended to encourage dataset creators to plan for dataset maintenance and communicate this plan with dataset consumers.</description>
            <questions>
                <Q0>Who is supporting/hosting/maintaining the dataset?</Q0>
                <Q1>How can the owner/curator/manager of the dataset be contacted (e.g., email address)?</Q1>
                <Q2>Is there an erratum?</Q2>
                <Q3>Will the dataset be updated (e.g., to correct labeling errors, add new instances, delete instances)?</Q3>
                <Q4>If the dataset relates to people, are there applicable limits on the retention of the data associated with the instances (e.g., were individuals in question told that their data would be retained for a fixed period of time and then deleted)?</Q4>
                <Q5>Will older versions of the dataset continue to be supported/hosted/maintained?</Q5>
                <Q6>If others want to extend/augment/build on/contribute to the dataset, is there a mechanism for them to do so?</Q6>
                <Q7>Any other comments?</Q7>
            </questions>
            <messages>
                <M0>Please be as thorough as possible.</M0>
                <M1 />
                <M2>If so, please provide a link or other access point.</M2>
                <M3>If so, please describe how often, by whom, and how updates will be communicated to users (e.g., mailing list, GitHub)?</M3>
                <M4>If so, please describe these limits and explain how they will be enforced.</M4>
                <M5>If so, please describe how. If not, please describe how its obsolescence will be communicated to users.</M5>
                <M6>If so, please provide a description. Will these contributions be validated/verified? If so, please describe how. If not, why not? Is there a process for communicating/distributing these contributions to other users? If so, please provide a description.</M6>
                <M7 />
            </messages>
            <answers>
                <A0>Immunitrack ApS.</A0>
                <A1>By email, at: mprachar @immunitrack.com.</A1>
                <A2>No</A2>
                <A3>There is a possibility that more instances will be added from the public sources (MS data).</A3>
                <A4>The dataset does not relate to people.</A4>
                <A5>No. Not expected to be a problem.</A5>
                <A6>It is possible to extend the MS data, IEDB is a great source (www.iedb.org).</A6>
                <A7>No</A7>
            </answers>
        </category_7>
    </questionnaire>
</root>